All right folks.
We'll get started welcome to the final session
file time slots off the conference we hope you've had a great
conference so far and we'll try to finish often a good note
...super encouraged by how many of you are here we found out we got the last time slot
...the conference who are like hmm's will anybody be here.
So, thank you for coming here and just as a quick level set
how many of your writing code today against address storage?
Ok, many of your awesome so we're going to do a sort
of a three-part talk here we're going to do a quick overview of our storage
and all its capabilities show you a bunch of code show you how to get started where
they're going to talk about storage from the dev ops perspective and how you keep
your service running and then we'll end with design patterns both existing
wants a new design patterns that we've added since the last time loosens
...conferences so let's first get started with
the short video as people come in?
Of course the session feedback please don't forget that will leave this up at the end of
the talkwe really appreciate your feedback and comments especially so
do let us know that's how we improve.
Media start this off.
The xbox live service...of the social experiences on the xbox consul things like competing with other
players...other players insane game...the cooperative
...your competitively and also tracking the progress we hope that by
providing social features ortiz challenges features...things that kind of go
beyond game play that we're able to give you a much better more enjoyable experience
...a platform or services...asher tables for their base layer of
...out where storage capsule so at the end of the day you use natural...account for
...table storage...use many of those free...do that because we want to go to get more
about elastic capacity of asher and also because we don't want to...data one place for things like
disaster recovery purposes so every service and xbox...a common platform base measure
tables to figure out where each...status xbox we
...a new feature millions of people use that feature almost instantaneously
that's a significant amount of load...spent the last ten or twelve years trying to figure out how to
handle scale for a removed asher storage were concerned that
you could this partner service to the same thing that we're already doing a term and it was fantastic that could
...that we've never seen an issue where we deployed in
...feature and asher with the bottleneck that caused us to not have that feature
work as we looked future we were able to get things done faster and try things out more and you're going to make mistakes
...do...great stuff...we can iterate on these things the faster and more likely
the automaker customers happy we want xbox
always got the best place to play games and that doesn't just
mean that we have the best games but also those games are more fun...the more and more data
that can push the system in...more data we can retain and...process the user is
...with experience and that's always...have to think about how many more service...
do this or homework's hard...to have to provide store all this stuff we can just know...that
almost infinite capacity will be there we can build almost anything imagines...
this is the story of how one of our earliest partners when xbox
was building xbox one they decided to bed their business on as your as
your storage and now pretty much anything you do with your
xbox runs through asher they run hundreds of thousands of cores
run petabytes of data through our system and it's fair to say you can't really
turn on your xbox without touching many parts of asher and this is
true across the xbox set of services
...xbox live and your social
graph your friends your achievements activities you've taken all of that ends up
in table storage of game dvr you record game clips that comes in the blob
...encoded the as
your media services xbox make music and video the master
catalogues encodings everything is stored and...blob storage so this is kind of just
as a short set of the features that run on
...your storage blobs and tables so... in this is kind of
our journey and figuring out how to help our partner
and internal microsoft teams run first and bestmark platform so we can get
that scale and then bring that to our partners are, you know, developers all of
...and we'll talk about this... talk through how asher storage can really get you
there so the first thing to start with is are infrastructure scale
...well over a million...today we're ninety...more than both eight of us
...google combined you know, india errors are newest announce region and we have
in many other regions as well casual storage is an every single one of these
regions it's a foundational building-block along with computer networking and every
other as your service...many microsoft services build on top of it in terms of our own scale for
the stored system we have well over fifty trillion objects
in our system we do six million transactions per second average
on our system across the world and, you know,
if that's a hard number to rap, you know, your minor around it's basically
a billion transactions every three minutes that's happening all
the time in the two or three minutes you heard that video and got this slide we've done a billion transactions
in our system we're also enough really focused on
being the most open platform for getting
your data regardless of what device or architecture
you're coming from we have rest api of course but we've also build client libraries
...dot net as you'd...java cplus-plus
...js android we just launches
...the library preview or working on...library and we have python ruby and
peach tree as well so our goal is really to abstract all of the, you know,
it's not fun to go build of rest transaction so we want
to go do that give you a good standard offering that you can then depend on regardless of
what platform a device your building on we're also really good at doing so
that hybrid storage between on from enterprises and...cloud?
The...and disaster recovery services as your site recovery run on top of
allergist storage you can have a really nice connection between all your on
cram machines and vietnam's do backups to disaster recovery restores into the
cloud we also have store simple and offering that allows you to build enterprise
tiered storage that done gets sent very efficiently and stored in the
...storage cloud we have a number of different data offerings
...number of different abstractions ranging
for unstructured storage to know sequel reliable queuing and persistent
...what kind of walk through each of these...give you
a quick overview and how to code against them or how to use them so let's start with the
base layer blobs so blobs and for each of these and abstractions I sort of have the
...summary can walk away within the case blob
it's highly scalable rest spaced object cloud objects
...right it's where you store files what would you
canonical think of storing and storage you would stored and blobs...two kinds of
...blog flops they're meant for sequential reads states where
you'd upload files download files...typically what you would be using
...page blobs which are optimized for their sparse files are optimized for random
access and they actually form the backbone of as your...
a service...discs so let's start by kind of jumping right into code
and seeing hey how do I get started working with blobs, you know, we'll go over here?
...with visual studio and open up a new project.
The first thing you notice once installed the...
dk is you have this cloud and quick starts in here.
Data services...quick start samples for blob storage tables and
will quickly run through those let's say I'm going to go and start this up getting a new project going.
So, I'm going to open up the program.
All right so right away I'm just going to start.
First thing that's going to do it's going to go get the new get package references
written restore them and we're up and running.
So, we're doing some blob operations we'll talk about what containers are block mobs are
...kind of doing block blobs and page blobs
and the sample kinda gets you up and running right away this isn't running right now against
...against the cloud if you notice it says.
You know,...store account one this is
a storage emulator running on your box so you can get started and...
your tasks run all your experiments without actually...the cloud and paying for transactions and all of that
so you can get started right away even offline right now in this room with no problems at all.
So, let's cut start kind of modifying this and looking at what we can do here.
Right now this is a pretty straightforward simple sample look at what it
does and then start modifying a little bit so here's my main I have some
block mob operations I have some page blob operations so let's jump in to the
...operations I have a
of object I'm working with here let me go ahead and exit here.
So, the first thing I'm going to look at is, you know,
what's in here I have an image them working with...upload also then have
a object hierarchy starting with a cloud storage account?
And, that's something that goes in and reads a connection string from app
conflict.
Will go take a look at that?
We then have a blob client that we create on the storage account we have a
container that we create on the blob client right?
And, all of these so far offline operations this is the
first operation that actually tries to connected emulator or to a storage account in the
cloud.
...couple of things to notice all the code in the
samples is asic we have a...and...api for all are api
...we strongly recommend of course that you use a sinking api
is and.
You know, this is kind of a way to look at this so let's...on
...start by taking the storage account actually and opening
up configured connecting this to the cloud.
Here's my storage connection string it says right now
use developments storage equals true I'm going to replace start.
With...string for a demo accounts that I've set up already.
And, what the shows here
is a couple of things one you have the protocol
and point you will typically said this...https?
The only reason you set http if you're doing development work and you want to debug this makes it a little
easier to work with a network tracer
...or what have you have...and then you have an account key okay?
So, we've set that up we've saved that let's run this again.
And, now as you can notice here I'm running against a.
Running against the asher...this is live code running we've
connected to this account demos fifteen and we've gone ahead and done some operations here.
So, let's look at what operations we were actually doing right so
we've kind of connected we've created a container
...object hierarchy or the mario data hierarchy for blob storage
is...within a...container all data
then you have a concept of a container think of it as a directory...you will that you can, you know,
set we isolation things are you can set
shared access signatures which allow you resource isolation you can do atomic operations against
the container like dropping everything and it and, then you store blobs inside
these containers so we create the container if it doesn't exist we then go ahead
and upload a block blob right so we go ahead and get a
...bob reference with ourimage that...uploading and we upload that so with
a single api can go ahead and upload and then go ahead and list all the blobs
in that container I download the blob again and then I delete
the blob right...just trying to clean-up so I'm going-to go ahead and comment this...
And, then go ahead and comment this out here.
So, we don't...the other thing I'm going to do is I'd like to access this blob once
it's created
so in the sample code is this little note about saying hey if you want to
set the container to be public you can go ahead and do that so I've just
uncommon to that line of code I'm going-to go ahead and run this sample again?
And, at this point I should be able to see the
block law and I'm going to show that you a couple of different ways.
The first of course is just let's go look at in...
So, simple enough I can richard...public.
But, if it weren't public I can also look at it and visual studio with the sdk you get
a nice little storage explore built-in I can open up storage here open up
the demos fifteen account and I can open up the blobs.
And, let's go look at our demo container block blob that...created and hear this
and it is utc yep nine fifteen so we're looking at this
and we can see that even for a private blob you can kind of go through and browse things as needed.
The other thing that we want to do is, you know, obviously this being a sample.
We don't have a lot of error handling here,
you know, in a production code...have exception handling...looking for
common exception codes and things like that catching them and doing something with them so,
I'm going to quickly insert a small snippet of code here and talk
to what that allows me to do so let's take this upload.
lob line and then replace it with my code.
And, what this code does is
...things the first thing is does is it overrides the operation
context client request id the client request id is
a field that the client library automatically generates for-you and gives you
good but you can override it with anything you want and the reason you'd want to do this
is typically a request for you is maybe a set of transactions
to storage and you want to tie them all together and look at them as one entity when you do your
dab odp story in this case I've just sort of said hey my client request ideas
...string?
And, the next thing I'm doing is adding a little bit of exception handling around here
right so I'm trying to upload the blob and if I havel problem I'm just going to
...the exception and log some information here so let's go ahead and run that again.
Let's see what we are.
So, I forgot to add a reference here.
And, what that was doing?
Basically even though it's some sort of the wrong place here.
Taking care of service point manager the default connection lebed is something that allows you to
the default connection limit for dot net is to connections if you're trying to do doesn't matter much for
this demo but if you're trying to do a lot moredata you can you want to set this a little bit
higher used in algal is very useful for table and tables and
...especially if you have small entities nagging
ties to aggregate data together before sending
on packets and it's really hard performance
...do in dealing with small amounts of data so let's try to compile that?
Gone ahead and run and.
You see here though it's also failed right
because I deleted by commented out the blob deletion I got a photo
nine error back that said hey this blob.
Already exists.
And, we give you a friendly...code we give you a daytime stab me give you
this thing which is a server request id and that's a unique id that
the service generates and sends back to in this is also useful we'll see later in our
demo we'll take this id and use it to
do some debugging all right so let me get rid of that let me copy this out.
All right so I'll just say that for now and get...here.
Coming back to our presentation.
Ok, so, that's kind of a quick overview of how to use...blobs and I think the big take away
their is you can get started very quickly very easily with
this quick start samples and you can explore and, you know, kind of branch out from there.
So, let's talk about tables.
Tables rr no sequel often they are use
anytime you want to store semi-structured...structured data and.
They're really about storing schema less entities the big feature that we give
use we do dynamic load balancing there's no real limit on the number of rows are the size of
the table you can grow as much as finer...was the size of an account and we
take care of observing which regions of your table are hot getting a lot of rights are
a lot of reeds and we load balance automatically across hundreds of servers in
our service so you don't never have to worry about,... what's my scale unit how do I do this
the other thing that we do is provide entity group transactions if you're trying
to do group transactions atomically we do have that within a
partition outdo node that we're key value store so
...really optimized for key value lookup where you provide us the partition key and the...and there
are other data offerings and as...if you're trying to do something more interesting a richer the
...of tables is really enormously high scale and also enormous
great cost efficiency if your data pattern fits what we offer
I'm going to come over here and show you a very quick preview of table
search mainly to point out that it looks and feels.
Exactly like.
Blob storage so you have here.
Sorry.
Again,
I have the same lines here and it layers said natal is more useful here but
let's look at what we're doing the table a...does the same thing starts with
the storage account gets a table client reference and then goes ahead and
creates the table if it doesn't exist.
Table operations.
For tables you need to have a cost, you know,
a entity...entity objects in this case we have a customer and
we've inherited from table entity and that's the allows you
to specify partition key and role key that really is
what are the indexes we allow and what you do your lookup spy?
Coming back here so inserting in
...doing and insert and actually and upsurge here insert or march
...retrieve that entity and we delete entity again just
as simple as operating with blobs let's go ahead and run this one as well.
And, you'll see does a couple of other things it also does batch inserts and batch
retrievals so that's kind of you know, just generated a little bit of load for the purposes of our
dev ops right so let's go back to.
Presentation.
...are reliable messaging system at scale accuser really useful when
you have other asher services that you've built and you need to
decouple your components and be able to scale them independently if you have your canonical sort
of web role worker role you'd want to q
...between them so you could hand-off work asynchronous
...to the workers and then your web role can scale independently for worker
roles right so you use it for this you also use it
for the scheduling asynchronous faster building any kind of workflows
...allow you to guarantee that work gets done so
the one feature that we have a something we call invisible message invisibility
timeout and basically what this means is once you dq a message you
can only decode with the timeout if
your worker crashes during processing off that message your message
will reappear in the...for another worker to
pick-up and complete we also provide an update message functionality so
you can periodically checkpoint your progress from a worker if you
Midway through a complicated process...hour starting
over of from scratch so those are two kind of interesting features to look at with
Not going to run the q demo it looks pretty similar to the blobs and
tables demo so there's a sample...known play with as well.
So, blob stables and...
Are sort of
...has offering if you will for asher store this is what you'd...against these
...the things that allow you to build your services on top of our data platform?
I'm going to leave you with this slide...not going to go over here but over here but it's a good reference
slide there's a nice little architecture
clean consistent architecture of api eyes and their access you know,
we have a set of...aps...service level for blobs...containers for tables
...tables...you have...and then you have api
is that manipulate either blobs table entities or q messages
...very consistent programming paradigm
...using one it's very easy to incorporate the others in your application.
So,...programming is blob stables and
...but you're probably also bringing other parts of your stack to
asher...might be bringing a model db cluster you might be bringing a
cassandra instance and you're probably going to run them on average are
infrastructure as a service either windows or linux ibm's.
We also provide the backing storage the persistent data storage for
...service
...both for your operating system this as well as any data you persist.
So, we https...data disks essentially a batch two-page blobs that
we talked about earlier optimized for random access the nice thing here is
you get three synchronous strongly consistent copies of your data when you write
and aggregated disc so you don't have to worry about what, you know,
redundancy and things like that every right when it's committed is committed to
tree different physical locations you can always...together for more performance if you
need and premium storage this our newest offering that just ga last week allows you
to build really scale-up workloads so let's take a quick look at
They're really useful if you're trying to have a workload that needs very
consistently low latency in the single digit milliseconds and very predictable high
...throughput with the new class of lms the ds use lms you can do as
much as sixty four thousand I ops...of a single vm thirty-two
terabyte of data and five hundred megabytes second of...throughput.
Again, here with prima storage even though it's
...as the based offering you get those three strongly consistent copy so you're not
needing to worry about data durability we have because it's
a provision offering you buy it a little bit differently from basic blob storage
you can abiding units of hundred-twenty a gigs five twelve or
time twenty-four gigabyte disks and you have different performance numbers for each one of those.
Files is another interesting offering whoops.
Measure files...allow you to get shared access
disks right shared this of the data this a persistent
...are attached to a vm their essentially like,
you know, a hard disk on that vm with files you can say here's my
smb of share that I can net use or...
and lenox and just habit work across many ibm's and have all the canonical things
...expect of shared disks just work right it's natively supported by the operated
...operating systems and it just works it's built on top of
smb two-point-one and there's no limits again on the number of shares you can create an actor storage
...each share can be up to five terabytes and size and about a thousand I
ops per share so this is really useful if
you're bringing legacy code basis entourage...and you need...needed a
story to share for configuration for logging for data whatever
...something else to consider when you...your code?
Other complementary asher data offerings, you know,
we just heard about data lake which is big data analytics within
...interface...building on top of...storage as well so all...data that you
...data like eventually comes to algebra jobs document db if you're more interested in
a json document store instead of in the no sequel family you want to look at document
dvd and of course you're interested in full-blown relational databases
...equal db gives you a great offering that's a manage database.
And, finally if you're looking
...would say I need a little bit more of rich q offerings
that pub sob in order delivery things like that you may want to look at service box.
So, after... kind of the architecture of storage is essentially built on top
of one common platform right we
have one distributed file system massive distributed file system.
Tens hundreds of petabytes of data in each region and you have a
scale out layer and a load balancing layer on top of that so that...
application layer we call it the stream layer is where used the data is physically store
and the partition layer is where all the metadata the indexing...of detection of
than in a...and dynamically load balancing it happens and finally on top
is the front-ends that you communicate with for with your rest calls you authentication
...all of that happens on top of those two layers so this is interesting because
by having one common software stack it really allows us to give you a
common feature set a very consistent look and feel for the programming
and the api...and it allows us to also give you
...pass on the economies of scale that we get by mixing
...block blob workloads with...table workloads
...q workloads so we can kind of makes all those workloads together do it very efficiently.
And, it also allows us to give you all of these capabilities, you know, for all of
our offerings right so if you look at scaleability we have per account we can do finer
terabytes of data twenty thousand transactions per second and up to ten gigs of
...gigabit of in wrestler twenty gigabit
so egress you have multiple durability options where the only cloud...provider
to provide automatic geo redundant storage where your data is asynchronous
...copied from the one datacenter we writing to another datacenter at least four hundred
miles away we also provide sla guarantees on our availability...you know,
we do have multiple access control and analytics capabilities but I'll
let my colleague jason kind of walk you through those things
where demos and other things so jason...
So, eventually...provide an introduction
...storage platform as well as what sort of how to actually get started writing
...applications when things I'm going to talk about is how do I
start thinking about preparing replication from when it goes into production last thing you
want to do is build a cloud scale application put it in production and not have processes in place
from monitoring or diagnosing issues when they do occur you can imagine at cloud scale
...one-in-a-million operations failing for our platform
main six operations failing every second that would be a lot of
...time chasing down issues that could be
spent of creating new features so we obviously
have extensive develops capabilities within a platform and we've exposed a lot of those...to actually use as well?
So,...do have to think about it was sort of this three different ways you want to think about sort of monitoring the
first is if you're selling a solution to...you...the eyes that you've committed
...customers and all that you're actually committing...you want to make sure the amazing secondly
want to try to identify issues before you customers do
...you've got the sort of service fundamentals service...service availability performance
scaleability capacity those sorts of things the wanna-be tracking on an ongoing basis.
...think about monitoring...to main ways to actually think about the first is outside
...this is way basically when you actually have agents running on the outside
of your application performing synthetic transactions simulating
...your actual uses behavior microsoft as a tool
...is also external products gomez and keynote
...a very good for this of outside in monitoring outside in is also a very good for actually isolating issues
to...network outages because quite often you'll have a person one region complaining
about network latency very hard to diagnose and these tools make it very
easy then this inside out and this is what I'm going to spend a majority of the time talking about whereby
within your application of instrumented it such that you can actually monitor...alerts
and then investigates as necessary the storage platform has two sets ofand,
capabilities metrics and logs that walk through ...libraries also include logging
but you can enable should you need to at times see may need to look at what's going on in the network
...out some tools of useful for that and if you think is actually issues with the actual with a
particular workload...availability ...a portable has a service health dashboard.
So, the first them to talk about is metrics basis really think about metrics
is equivalent to perf...and windows service-type environment
...by this forty different types of metrics that are available for blobs tables and
...and that allow you to actually monitor the house of those
capabilities one of the key differences is that even though you may have
...service has no flood of service...and the...we aggregate all of that information and actually
...the metrics are available a and hourly and minute level...the
all these very good for taking a look at sort of trends...last a week month so forth the
...and minute level...metrics a very good if you're actually trying to actually
determine app drill into a problem and the both metrics and...
and they actually specify granularity operation types that you want to log and retention policies
...metrics registered in tables logging information is stored in ...
All right I'm going to switch over to the new as...portal and what I'm going to do
is actually drill into storage accounts and storage account I've been running by
test application on a is over here today how test-tube and
...is take a look first of all it provides the top of the portal it was of some
...of things you can see...configured my account type outrage ers so this is sort of the
...them she was talking about whereby whenever I rights to my primary location
it's automatically getting replicated to a second location plus I can also read from
that second location which is very helpful when you building highly available applications
...walk you through some code that demonstrates that...I'm just going to collapse?
A mouse seems to be playing.
Interesting the slide and the mouse do not get along this line.
Collapse that.
...there.
And, what you can see here is dashboard and that is actually fully customizable right now what
is showing is the...requests?
And, sharing right now it's showing them for the last are also.
But, what I can do is at this chart
...of the mouses misbehaving and I can do a couple things here first of all I can actually change the time
range so first...have it set up right now for custom and drilling into a fifteen minute period but,
if I actually...to take a look at say passed out and I can also look at microsoft
...forty different characteristics of blobs
or tables haven't been using q so that's why didn't pop of that
and that could be looking at right now I'm looking at to requests I can save
...I can actually see we should actually see the data for the last hour and you can see
...about an hour before the presentation was getting my demo ready sequences of
...by...because I want to be a dashboard is not just the number of request that are interesting to
me one if the one of the largest sort of areas where I've seen customers
want resistances deployed...application...customers say it it's performing
...and it's...sporadic so here's a couple counters that...while...taking a look at into
and latency and average...latency what these metrics show you...several latency is the time that
we actually spent performing an operation on...service end-to-end latency I should try
to the time it takes from the client to establish a connection to the storage service the time it
...perform that operation and the times
...the up all the data to the actual...so it's a really good indicator of
when things maybe going wrong on the network so in this case you can see here and
...up every time it took for us server to actually perform the
operations was five milliseconds the average end-to-end latency was...hundred sixty four
milliseconds so you can see...sixty milliseconds just of network time involved in that request
...not to...that was from the hotel...those sorts of things but,
very useful ...so, for troubleshooting and the other thing...can do is very useful
fresh monitoring is you can actually create alerts so,
now...way...actually credit condition such as
...on latency?
Alerts.
Where I can basically specify?
That are specific metric maybe.
Average intern latency is greater than that's
a thousand milliseconds over the last five minutes when I said
...to my administrators so there's a good example of...you try to actually credit policy that allows you
to get ahead of the customers rather than them having you call you up and tell them that
something's going wrong you can credit policy along...size.
...I've just done that.
So, that's a quick look at metrics and one thing I didn't mention was the analytics platform.
And, this is not enabled by default so...we do recommend as while you're doing
a developments and create account go into the pool and enableboth
...metrics and definitely helpful when you have to stat troubleshooting.
So, metrics...you actually observe the behavior of application is system sometimes
...metrics information on own will give you
...what's going on we sort of gave an example that the oftentimes
...drill into log data to actually see what's going on so that's we have something called
blogs and think...in semis is sort of equivalent of biases locks every single rest
operation is performed can be logged and we allow you to a
...specify subset of those so, for example, you any
...updates to actually be logged you could do that as well if you want to actually reduce the size of the log files the
log entries includes...all the its information...would expect inside
...operation the endpoint was calls the time it took the size of the message all that sort
of stuff very useful for troubleshooting and what I'm going to do right now?
Is image...do this live
and see-saw earlier them she was?
And, performing set of operations against.
points and, what I'm going to do is you use a tool called a
...and which is sort of think about this is a file copy utility that allows
actually copy data from on premises to the cloud from the cloud batch on premises
and in this case what I'm going to do is actually copy all of the log files...creative of m she was actually running
his demo against them as fifteen...into my file system?
Well, see that's actually eighty four files
...copied and hopefully they will actually show up...
So, they're actually copied into their respective sort of workload
...copied and by blob by...and.
Finally and the log files basically structured...of
...five-minute intervals you open them up they're actually a little bit
...to actually do anything useful with...so one of the tools that we've
actually spent quite a lot of time working with is a tool called message analyzer...analyzers a for
...can download it actually came comes from the...written created met...which I'm sure many
people have used what this actually allows you to do is basically create a session
and what we can actually do is add files and what I'm going to do here...
...import all of the logs...just downloaded.
...in this case essential
...small amount of...we can just loaded and process and but if you actually had like
...with the data...a staff...and filter to specify stat time and end-time
...go through a logs...pull out the log entries that fall into that criteria you can also
establish an session filter.
And, if you wanted to actually have more advanced filtering such as looking for all status codes of three
hundred more you could do that.
...over here.
Once again.
So, associate import that data.
So, again, what we've got here is the default view of that data and we're going to do right now is actually choose we've got a
stores like...that which gives us like...strongly...view of the data and
the ability that she query at...match...
...behaving so you can actually see now all of...entries that we've actually just imported available in this
too which is kind of useful but,
it gets even more interesting is still an awful lot of data and I'm trying to actually work out why that
...on the...what we can actually do is actually rights strongly typed queries
...as your storage log dot letter anything maybe that has a status
code of more than two hundred ninety nine because that tends to buy something,
something...expenses...so what we've come through now is actually filtered through all
the data and if you remember them she also she customize the client request
id so we can actually see straight away their the actual the particulates and the
specific operation that found and is here we can...look as a put blah-blah-blah aeration
...four nine four nine scenarios...some kind of concurrency issues
occured and straight away they can actually have a pretty good sense of what was going on and sort of give it to
uses this tools also very useful finding patterns any data so we basically got a number of different sort
of best practices that we've identified and, you can actually search for that things that
...those mentioned there's a...in here for actually detecting if you should be enabling neighbor
...one last thing this tools very useful for is...
You'll...that she will come back to the second and...of...
Okay, so, we talked about metrics to about logs.
We also have...logging so this is basically inside each about client libraries
...consistent...approach so actually doing
logging very useful for enabling when you actually try to actually debug.
The next thing you want to be thinking about is quite often especially wave got networking issues
if you sort of getting sporadic network access from a specific region and you may
...that using something like wash uncle message analyze which allows...capture network trays
...tcp levels if there's something wacky going on lots of reconnect those sorts of things
...just right now one of the challenges there is the sort of end up with
...is server-side log data...networkssort of one...network analytics...
put together I've got these client-side logs you can also log...actually stitching that together is really
difficult when is cool things about message analyzers actual as a correlates and those
...files together safe remember we have that correlation id that we actually
...clients actually also in hp...header...inside the stores
...so...in this sort of...can...I've already loaded all of
the client-side logs from a test of...lots and network trace...as you go
into particular requests see the requested response and,
I could actually...start looking through the record what...queries again not an overly useful
...what I can also do is basically groupthe data
...request a which point now what actually see as a correlated view of the data
remote to a where,
for example, if you actually have a specific...request id that...looking for?
You can then actually you could searcher is...filter then you can basically see what was
going on inside the client applicationstrongly typed...
you could actually query against if you wanted to so forth so really useful tool for troubleshooting.
And, that's the correlation that we just spoke about.
All right so that's sort of a couple sort of.
Things to be thinking about when you actually think about planning
...for an deployment what I'm going to do right now is sort of
...number different design patterns the may also want to think about what...designing your application
this is just a sample we have an awful lot about the patterns that we basically
...time...available sort of...and samples
...documentation...show that a...a new which is sort of why we wanted to talk to them today...to talk
about application encryption this is a capability that just released this week for out dot net
client library and coming soon for the libraries and the ability to actually do
direct data access using delegated authorizationthis is a model we supported for
a long-time and recommended model for many scenarios and the ability to large-scale
append operations critical for big data login scenarios but also useful for a number
...the snares as well and if I'm going to talk about how to build highly available applications using our
...jump into encryption so this week we've ...to a dot net library that actually allows the
library to automatically encrypted data before sending it to storage and then when you retrieved data
...automatically tikrit that data and integrates seamlessly into our current
and sdk safer block clubs you existing api...follow
...I had basically three lines of code...we actually support
full blob uploads we'll say obviously support a full...download we also set pratt
...support range get operations on retrieval as well for
...to read inserting replace entities and including specifying what
subset of attributes on an entity you want encrypted
...batch operations...obviously each messages individual encrypted...anything with
clients encryption is a capability that probably everybody in the room could be...themselves but playing with
...libraries is not really find for everyone for anyone so that's what we've done the hard work
and we've actually follow the standard emulating encryption model
...ik rotation and, we've basically...away
with ensure that the actual format...the objects in an encrypted format can be
...will from different language client libraries as well?
H object
...self-contained and metadata we actually store the references in the actual algorithm
...fresh encrypting am and if you're interested all the...codes available on
...up...the challenges with application encryption as it's all very well to encrypt all if you data
...a lot of...worried that what happens if you lose the key how do I
decremented at the...you can't say one of things we recommend...you want
...be thinking medic key management capability at the same time as
and vesting encryption microsoft this year is actually...
released key votes which is a key management solution that allows you to manage rotate a
...accesskeys actually sort of another point...the client library encryption and
...microsoft can never see these case some botha solutions being built...way you can
applications and you can sort of rest show that there's no way for us to actually
encrypted data when you're using cable fetching managing
...and the master case actually ...rest with a
...highly secure and tamper proof authentication and for interacting with
...up requires eighty credentials and this also allows you actually think about sort of
separation of concerns and show that the uses who can actually manager case it different from the uses are
actually running applications that actually performing operations on data the storage library that we just
talk about the extensions they also am enable
...integration so again ...very quickly get up and running and then if you want
...case manage by...trivial...I'm going to...into a quick demo of right now?
Right so antithesis acre time just opened up.
When you actually download
alleges client library this appointed to samples that actually show blobs tables
...and files being encrypted?
I'm going to take a look at...just focus on the blah...us pretty straightforward.
And, you can...api is exactly the same as...and she was just walking through basically
credit ga cannes credit climbs sort of proxies the request the service credit
contain of all...good stuff what we've done that...basically added three lines of code the
first and code is an rsa case so this is basic one of the
extension points we have within the application is that we can actually locally you can choose
encrypted data using symmetrical asymmetric algorithm or if you want to you can have key
...upon performing the actual encrypted...operations and if we using keyboard instead of rsa
key would have this sort of cave...to...equipment provider and that once retrograde...in this case
...an hour shaky...encryption policy so, basically...in this case
...encryption policy...it's just preference in the key that which is created here
then finally and we have this request options capability where all of the storage operations already have
...and extensibility point way can when you actually performing...can specify things what
location to get request from so forth all we've done is extended that to allow you to actually
specified encryption policy and that's exactly what we've got here.
So, I will run this but, I will tell you.
Encryption demos tend to be fairly and interesting and.
But, we've got here is some running
...in the background what we can see here is was basically a number of difference
...basically uploaded the actual binary data them
or you can see the on-again everybody should be...that's not to adjustable and then
we can say-so again what we've done here is we...our upload blob capability under the cover that performs a number
things actually breaks the data into blocks and then it submits a
block list which is how we sort of commit the final blog and blob in the actual blockers
separation you can see here that we've got some extra ...exist in this which
...readable view you can see we've got this x microsoft metadata encryption data and that's
we can see basically was...sort of...the data self-contained we've got encryption mode
...full blob we've got the rapped content key and this is rackets a
...two forms of the encryption that are...we actually encrypt all of the
...using a symmetric k then we encrypt that symmetric
...with the asymmetric key in this case or could have been...encrypting at and what we have to
distort the encrypted content encryption key and a reference to the algorithm that was used
...encrypting...content encryption key and that's all
...metadata and a again we've actually we submitted it we can also we've got
...get request...should pull data back
and again it's encrypted so-you nothing really interesting to see that?
the key here is anybody's using a...libraries trivial to get up and running.
Take a quick look at table's kind of interesting ventures to show you how you can actually use the and table entity
object to find your and entities one of the nice things we've done here is basically
...we have to do is a dawn seven attribute the...encrypted with encrypt property and then at that point
will be encrypted automatically under the covers...there's also a key vote
getting status sample this one does require a little bit more time...that she...to create key
...votes you've got a registry replication you've got to get some eighty credentials those sorts of things
so I want run...threat right now but the actual the application there and
...basically everything you need to get up and running so that's encryption.
Thank you is that and them...a long-time coming.
So, well-run subjects of soto security and we...about
...encrypted data something else is critical think about is access
...has three main means of actually performing access control first of all
...can use a storage account k and that's a sort of actually done this gives
you full access to the data you can actually creating updating and
...answer quite often you don't want to have all of
you end-users any certainly would not want mobile devices to be using your storage account
k because essentially I'm trusted we also have capability code
...access signatures thing about this as sort of delegated authorization we can actually
credit token that grant's a limited restricted set of writes for
a limited period of time very useful for large number of scenarios and we'll talk more about
essential the third option we have is public which is what...shared which was an for blob
storage you can also static container to be public...point you can access
...browser and sort of you can do any read operation against
celestial into shared access signatures because these are actually the one that we recommend for most applications
...you actually with security's important there's actually a number of different capabilities you can do first of all
the can specify what resources you want to grant access to contain is blobs
...tables within tables you can also specify ranges of data so if...actually
and building...application...to...a different pk for different customize you could actually
...as tokens for those specific key ranges very soon
...have accounts as which basically gives you account wide control to a
app storage account very useful for tool and companies anybody building storage explore right now you have to
ask people for the full storage county instead you can just ask them for a says key that gives
account access...in of these provide read...late all the different
commission capabilities you can also specify ability time start time and time to other things that
coming soon and the ability to actually restrict access to a specific ip address
very useful for financial services companies, for example,
one this the...show that...data if the applications arnie actually allowed to work from a set
at the address you can actually prevent that and also the ability lock-down
...protocol http or https at the bottom you can see the
...just a string of text and you added on to the url and that url
you can basically them perform the operation against the data...this case is an operation against storage
account sy is
basicallyexpiration time for the token si which is highlighted read is the
...if the resource type...this time...which is a container and sp is the permission that's the
...the list capability the string...the signature the signature can only have been created by
...storage account came we validate that on the back-end and that's how we determine
...the resources valid
another says tokens actually provide some interesting scenarios so first of all what allows you to do
is ensure the client's can access storage directly so if we didn't
...tokens and you wanted to actually have access control strategy what he would have to do would be build
...access layer on top of storage and then the challenge would be you'd have to work at a...you...base
...pain in the neck specially for these mobile and it scenarios we've
got very spiking very large workloads...you can do instead is issue
assess token to each of your applications that allows us applications
...treacherous storage very easy for you and it's also suitable
for entrusted devices obviously and also good for web and javascript scenarios we
have...support...the...token enables...to actually x
axis storage directly also good for a big data scenarios and you can actually issue
...token designing the ability to write and read not...say use of
...logging auditing those things speaking a big data one of the challenges
...see a lot is the ability to actually log large amounts of data very quickly and
...created a new type of blob
...append blob this is actually created for the data like product
...heard about today and all this week because today if you wanted to actually append
data to the end of a blob...to do two things first of all those a series of api said to
...to get...to uploaded...actually had to submit the...three operations for every append kind
of time-consuming the other thing was if you have multiple clients doing that then have to work at
...actually synchronized the
...don't actually overwrite each other's data very difficult to do so we've got a new api
called...blob single operation
...append blob as a single...if we can have tens of thousands of clients
...appliance writing directly the api as follows same conventions a
block and capability say it'd be very easy to get right into the quick code sampled
...went...it's exactly the same is blah-blah-blah for all intents and purposes the
amp one final thing I wanted to talk about was designing highly available applications so,
anything storage provides...events with the anyone...by...
to actually have data replicated across regions...in addition to that you can also
specify the second region and enables read access?
So, if you actually build your application with this in mind you actually get for nine-zero availability that we committee
by sla plant libraries include retry policies
have a default algorithm which is exponential back off and what this means is
that the actual client libraryallows...actually specify primary
...secondary as its retry policy it will first try read
...an operation on the primary if that fails
then go to the secondary and versus a very sort of useful way for actually dealing with sort
of trends in faults in particularso,
the retry operation is stateless so it doesn't mean that one thing you have to think about
the catastrophic outages we may lose the primary region or...upgrade which
is very common scenario you might want to actually do two things one have you application work and read any
...at least some functionally still available but secondly what you don't
want to do is have every single operation...the primary...which the second-rate so there's a pattern
...short-circuited which is an well-taken look at and...of a work as...implementation
of that shelving the other thing that you...do when building nih application is simulate
server-side failures and this is an ask we get a lots I'm going to show you how to do that right now
...the kinds of conditions he could run into production you want to make sure the
...you're actually doing development and quickly touch on the short-circuit pattern so
again retry policies are ideal for trends in failures but,...second pattern prevents
...application for repeatedly retrying...more severe issues short-circuit
break can automatically detect resources come back...and switch back to primary switch
application back to rewrite it the fundamental the...of the most important capability of taking advantage of
...within the client library we have a retrying event that you can tap into
...what I'm generates every time the retrying event is called it means
something's failed we're doing a retry I'm doing so some very simple logic
crime basically just establishing a threshold certain number of re tries...a certain period of time
and...switch the app to read-only mode and I'm going to get all of my data from the
second location so I will demonstrate this quickly?
I'm also going to demonstrate away to actually generate the actual server-side faults.
And, here's the shows are getting pattern and implemented so, again,
it's basically just a standard block storage sample of retry
...which is basically discounts I've got a threshold right now...for one which is basically just for
the purposes of a demo then what I'm going to do is once we switch over to
the secondary imaginal of our operations in the secondary you could do wanted-to things you could have a time
...every ten minutes you might want to check of the primaries back-up that require background...look a little bit
mcnally so all I'm doing is every twenty operations I'm going to see if the primaries back-up if it is with
...but to...so again it's basically...events some typing into one is the
trite retrying logic essentially keep...the number of re transitive occured
...threshold...is actually change the and
default request options location mode to secondary whereby all the operations
...the secondary at that point we're going to do is basically every time
an operation succeeds where
we're actually reading from the secondary I'm keeping track of another counter which is where
we basically say if after twenty operations on the secondary and,
then go actually switch back to the primary and hopefully everything's got that I'm
going to run this applications very simple application and all it's doing is basically p indicator
reading for the primary and indicator reading from the secondary now what I'm going to do is going to
fiddler phil has an awesome capability called an auto responder what I've done has built a
...and that allows me to simulate five-three said the era so you can see here
in the url right here we've got...how...which is a primary if I go
...this basically five-three you can actually see now let me just...
courses application what phyllis doing now is basically intercepting all messages
address tagging this url...sending back a
...message which is something that typically...can do something very difficult
...scenarios to actually simulate but phyllis helping us do that and
...can actually see here basically we've got the red message...basically we
...the request for listening...five-three which point with then got twenty raids that
occur from the secondary is can see that basically...added to the url and,
then we basically try to primate because fiddler was still running we end up going back to the secondary so let's
...continue the applications so continue and go back here you can see here the basically
...reading primary
...the era that's when we switch service secondary if I get to fiddler now basically to say with
the five-three what you see is we come back to the primary so really good example of how
to actually build a highly available application and also how to actually use tools I
...to help you tester applications and not have to wait
until production to actually see these types of issues?
And, got to last
...that announcements and resources...quickly here
so just kind of a quick summary of announcements ga announcements premium storage
...last week are cplus-plus
...library is ga as well mouse if you're using native code go
...preview and things are previous coming soon as
you're files is moving towards ga we have technical support now available for it we have new
research manager you've heard a lot about it at this conference storage supports the new
resource manager clients encryption you saw we have examine library
that's releases while and depend blog...improvements...coming soon
and ios library coming soon and the import-export service that allows you import data
...service or exported is becoming available nutshell in japan soon
...summary, you know, kind of look at
...documentation to kind of continue your learning from the session
...kind of really work hard and improving the documentation and
...dot com we've also written a bunch of detailed white papers like the one
on table designers one of the most complicated things from working with as your storage
as a thirty page document but that's really...organizer
...you need there's...on monitoring and diagnosing that really goes more into detail
a along the lines of what we talked about today in the dev ops guide and all
...of course always on the blog...also
pave as engineering team very close attention to both the msdn forms and stack
...anything that comes in tag...we're looking at it quite
regularly and if you need to reach us on twitter as well we can be reached so thank
you again thanks for coming thanks listing all the way to the...of a couple minutes over.
And, I'll leave you with the session feedbacks will be.